<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Math Lacome</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Math Lacome</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling intensity vs time.</title>
      <link>/post/model-peak-intensity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/model-peak-intensity/</guid>
      <description>One of the challenges to assess match demands is that the intensity and density of actions is likely time-independent, i.e., the longer the period, the lower the average intensity. Delaney et al. proposed to model match-related locomotor intensity vs. time relationship during matches using a power relationship. We used this method in a recent paper to examine at which extent different SSG formats could be used to either under- or overload the running- and/or mechanical- demands of competitive matches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualising force load distribution over time</title>
      <link>/post/sparkline-disbalance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sparkline-disbalance/</guid>
      <description>Recently, interest for GPS-embedded accelerometers variables has grown. Indeed, while classic locomotors variables give many pieces of information about the external load, little is known about how players’ cope with this load in return. GPS-embedded accelerometers, in return, allow the calculation of promising variables and among them, Force load. Force load refers to the sum of estimated ground reaction forces during all foot impacts, assessed via the accelerometer-derived magnitude vector ( Lacome et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using external load to estimate HR responses.</title>
      <link>/post/hr-prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hr-prediction/</guid>
      <description>In my last post, we saw a method to perform simple between-players normalisation to get first insights on players’ “performance” status. Like every model, this one has some known limitations and thus, it is important to use it in combination with other models to create a full stream of information. To overcome the limitations inherent to the use of this method, examining the dose-response relationship between workload and immediate physiological responses (or more simply generic models of work efficiency, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to compare one performance with previous ones</title>
      <link>/post/performance-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/performance-comparison/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to providing reports to the coaching staff or players, the first impression is always important. Within 5 seconds, a coach can decide not to have a look at your report. Within 5 seconds, it is always the design and overall aspect of the report which makes a difference, rarely the underlying analyses. In its brilliant paper Want to see my report, Coach, Martin Buchheit talk about the importance of effective sports science support and rank the attractiveness of the reports among the most important elements to take into account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readiness or Between-player normalisation</title>
      <link>/post/readiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/readiness/</guid>
      <description>We (Martin Buchheit, Ben M. Simpson &amp;amp; me) recently published a paper dealing with monitoring training status with GPS. If this paper, we argue that “Since player activity patterns are more heavily influenced by contextual variables (e.g. rules, coaches’ interventions, scoreline, drills used) than players’ current fitness status 1, locomotor-related variables (level 1 and 2) may not be the most appropriate to directly monitor players’ training status.”
We proposed that player activity normalisation relative to the mean or median of the team (or a sub-group of player) could be another way to look at the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>/post/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Why am I doing this blog?I’m Mathieu Lacome, a sports scientist working in elite football with over 10 years of experience in team-sport. A part of my job is to think about how we can improve the way we are collecting data, what we can do with it and how to report findings to the coaching staff or players.
Over the last 10 years, data feeds increased exponentially. Today, after every single game, data providers such as Opta or Stats produce a large amount of data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>