<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Monitoring on Math Lacome</title>
    <link>/tags/monitoring/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Monitoring on Math Lacome</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/monitoring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling intensity vs time.</title>
      <link>/post/model-peak-intensity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/model-peak-intensity/</guid>
      <description>One of the challenges to assess match demands is that the intensity and density of actions is likely time-independent, i.e., the longer the period, the lower the average intensity. Delaney et al. proposed to model match-related locomotor intensity vs. time relationship during matches using a power relationship. We used this method in a recent paper to examine at which extent different SSG formats could be used to either under- or overload the running- and/or mechanical- demands of competitive matches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualising force load distribution over time</title>
      <link>/post/sparkline-disbalance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sparkline-disbalance/</guid>
      <description>Recently, interest for GPS-embedded accelerometers variables has grown. Indeed, while classic locomotors variables give many pieces of information about the external load, little is known about how players’ cope with this load in return. GPS-embedded accelerometers, in return, allow the calculation of promising variables and among them, Force load. Force load refers to the sum of estimated ground reaction forces during all foot impacts, assessed via the accelerometer-derived magnitude vector ( Lacome et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using external load to estimate HR responses.</title>
      <link>/post/hr-prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hr-prediction/</guid>
      <description>In my last post, we saw a method to perform simple between-players normalisation to get first insights on players’ “performance” status. Like every model, this one has some known limitations and thus, it is important to use it in combination with other models to create a full stream of information. To overcome the limitations inherent to the use of this method, examining the dose-response relationship between workload and immediate physiological responses (or more simply generic models of work efficiency, i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>